Guide to the Stan Steiner Papers, ca. 1940-1987 M0700
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series III. Manuscripts by Steiner
  - The Jaguar and the Petrol: outlines y contracts n.d. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - The Jaguar and the Petrol: document n.d. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Jaguar and the Petrol: October [1977] trip 1977 Oct. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Jewish Conquistadors: America's first Cowboys? 1984 -1985 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - The Kid Goes West: carbons n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Kid Goes West: notes n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - La Raza: interviews n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - La Raza: notes n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - La Raza: outlines and Manuscript notes n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - La Raza: papers by Chicanos in an Albuquerque High School n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - La Raza: publicity [1 of 3] 1969 -1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - La Raza: publicity [2 of 3] 1969 -1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - La Raza: publicity [3 of 3] 1969 -1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - La Raza: outlines n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - La Raza: notes [1 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - La Raza: notes [2 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - La Raza: notes [3 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - La Raza: notes [4 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - La Raza: notes [5 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - La Raza: notes [6 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - La Raza: notes [7 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - La Raza: notes [8 of 8] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Last Horse n.d. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    TMs (carbons), 58 pp.
  - The Last Horse: Thompson, Robert n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Last Horse: Holt 1969 -1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Legend of Eddie O'Tough: notes, etc. [1 of 6] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Legend of Eddie O'Tough: notes, etc. [2 of 6] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    includes: "The Watchman and the ambush of Pablito," TMs, 18 pp.
  - The Legend of Eddie O'Tough: notes, etc. [3 of 6] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    TMs, pp. 1 -50
  - The Legend of Eddie O'Tough: notes, etc. [4 of 6] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    TMs, pp. 51 -100
  - The Legend of Eddie O'Tough: notes, etc. [5 of 6] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    TMs, pp. 101 -150
  - The Legend of Eddie O'Tough: notes, etc. [6 of 6] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    TMs, pp. 151 -177
  - Letter from the Southwest: It's still God's country n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Literary notes n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    "The Giants of the Earth " and "After the fall" TMs, 14 pp.
  - Literature of the American Indians, Notes thereon 1970 June (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Little Daughters of Mary n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    TMs (Carbons), 12 pp.
  - Los Angeles Times Reviews; Owen Wister, Greg Matthews c. 1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    "The making of the Western Hero" TMs
  - Lost Dreams: Indian papers and reports n.d. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Lost Dreams: clips n.d. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Lost Dreams: contract 1986 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Lost Dreams: notes n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Lost Dreams: outlines n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Lost Dreams: series n.d. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Love and Death of Unamuno n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Love in a covered wagon n.d. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Love in a covered wagon n.d. (Box 8, Folder 22)
    TMs, 31 pp.
  - Love of a grizzly bear n.d. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    TMs (2 copies), 14 pp.
  - The Man of God and the God of Man n.d (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The Man who invented OPEC [1 of 3] 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Man who invented OPEC [2 of 3] 1974 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The Man who invented OPEC [3 of 3] 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Man who wore monogrammed silk BVDs n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    TMS (carbons), 6 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [1 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    TMS, 16 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [2 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Foreward, TMs, 6 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [3 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    "The Garden of Adam," TMs, 19 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [4 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    "The New Eves," TMs, 30 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [5 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    "The Children of Macho," TMs, 29 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [6 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    "Behold me in a wigwam," TMs, 28 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [7 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    "Call me Ishmael," TMs, 32 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [8 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    "The Frontier woman's man," TMs, 39 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [9 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    "The real vigilantes of the West," TMs, 32 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [10 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    "Manhood: Essays on Western Masculinity," TMs, 19 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [11 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    "Prologue to Manhood," TMs, 30 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [12 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    "Prologue," TMs, 21 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [13 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    "The new Westerners," TMs, 24 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [14 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [15 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    "The Westerners: The birth of the New West: a book proposal," TMs, 23 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [16 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [17 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    "The Westerners: The birth of the New West: a book proposal," TMs, 25 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [18 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    "Religion on the Frontier: first draft," TMs, 27 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [19 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    TMs, 22 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [20 of 97] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [21 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    "The Marlboro Man," TMs, 40 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [22 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    "The Marlboro Man," TMs, 10 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [23 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    "Man: The History of American Manhood," TMs, 11 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [24 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    "Man: The History of American Manhood," TMs, 18 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [25 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    "The Garden of Adam: Manhood in America: The New Book," TMs, 34 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [26 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    "The All American Man," TMs, 11 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [27 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    "The All American Man," TMs, 12 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [28 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    "The Garden of Adam: Manhood in America: The New Book," TMs, 35 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [29 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    "Prologue: The Image of Man," TMs, 40 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [30 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    "The Origins of Manhood," TMs, 13 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [30.1 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    "Epilogue: The Future of Man, and Beyond," TMs, 2 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [31 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    "The Machos: The rise and fall of the American Male," TMs, 9 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [32 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    "The Origins of Manhood," TMs, 18 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [33 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    "I. The Garden of Adam," TMs, 22 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [34 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    "II. The New Eyes," TMs, 32 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [35 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    "VIII. The New Machos," TMs, 41 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [36 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    "The Mexican!," TMs, 7 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [37 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    TMs, 3 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [38 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [39 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    "Real horses, mythic riders," TMs, 30 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [40 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [41 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [42 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    "Notes on the Cosmic Cowboys," Across the Board.--Vol. 21, no. 2 (1984 Feb): 1 -5
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [43 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [44 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    TMs, 34 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [45 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    "Mythic riders, real horses," TMs, 4 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [46 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [47 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [48 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [49 of 97] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    "The lawman and the gunman," TMs, 76 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [50 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    "I. The Garden of Eden," TMs, 22 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [51 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    "II. The New Eves," TMs, 32 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [52 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    "The Children of Macho," TMs, 24 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [53 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [54 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [55 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    "Behold me in a Wigwam," TMs, 46 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [56 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    "Politics and Cowboys," TMs, 7 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [57 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [58 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    "Call me Ishmael," TMs, 34 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [59 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    TMs, 4 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [60 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [61 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [62 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [63 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    "Prologue to Manhood," TMs, 31 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [64 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [65 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [66 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    TMs, 41 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [67 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [68 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [69 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    TMs, 19 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [70 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [71 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [72 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [73 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    "Frontiers," TMs, 15 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [74 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [75 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    "Westward Ho! Ye merry Gentlemen!," TMs, 18 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [76 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    "The Indian Maidens and Eve," TMs, 20 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [77 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    "Seeking the Sun in the West: Land as Paradise," TMs, 13 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [78 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [79 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [80 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [81 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 32)
    "Black Virgins of Spain," TMs, 6 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [82 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    "Lincoln on Rape," TMs, 6 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [83 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 34)
    "The Hatred and the Loved," TMs, 4 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [84 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [85 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [86 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    "Lombroso, The Female Offender and Tribal Women," TMs, 3 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [87 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [88 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [89 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [90 of 97] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [91 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [92 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [93 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [94 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [95 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    "Pedro Martyr on Native Women," TMs, 13 pp.
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [96 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Manhood: manuscripts and outpages [97 of 97] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Manhood: publicity n.d. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Manhood: The Frontier Woman's Man n.d. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Manhood: Love in a Covered Wagon n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Lecompte, Janet. "The Independent women of Hispanic New Mexico, 1821 -1846"
  - Manhood: The Male God n.d. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Manhood: The Mountain Man n.d. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    TMs, 35 pp.
  - Manhood: The New Eve n.d. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Manhood: The Children of Macho n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Manhood: Call me Ishmael n.d. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Manhood: The Man of the Cloth and the Man of God n.d. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Manhood: The Cosmic Cowboys n.d. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Manhood: The Frontierswoman's man n.d. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Manhood: The man of La Macho [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Manhood: The man of La Macho [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Manhood: The masculine west [UNM 81 course outline and book list] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Manhood: on machismo by Chicanas [interview with Dolores Huerta and Maggie Alvarado; Synopsis of "Mujer"] n.d. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Manhood: the superb notes n.d. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Manhood: Daughters of the Blue Dragon n.d. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Manhood: notes 1975 Apr. (Box 12, Folder 25)
    Witt, Shirley. "La Mujer de Valor" TMs, 35 pp.
  - Manhood: The Lover Man [1 of 3] 1975 Apr. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Manhood: The Lover Man [2 of 3] 1975 Apr. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Manhood: The Lover Man [3 of 3] 1975 Apr. (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Manhood: Androgeny n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Meers, Sr. Elaine, OSF., "Perceptions of Androgeny: Fact or Fiction?" TMs, 27 pp.
  - Manhood: matriarchy 1981 Nov. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Monroe, Suzanne. "The Myth of Matriarchy" TMs, 6 pp.
  - Manhood: the erotic horsemen and horsewomen n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    "The Erotic Horsemen," TMs, 22 pp.
  - Manhood: The Biblical Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Manhood: The Ranch women [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Manhood: The Ranch women [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Manhood: student papers [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Duffey-Ingrassia, P.M. "Through and Beyond Radical Dictates," TMs, 10 pp.
  - Manhood: student papers [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Holgerson, Larry. "Phoenix," TMs, 6 pp.
  - Manhood: student papers [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    "A Myth on the Origin of Macho,"
  - Manhood: The Shadows in the Walls of the Cave n.d. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Manhood: The Father Earth n.d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Wiley, Patti. "Make an effort to remember, or failing that, invent" TMs, 22 pp.
  - Manhood: The Phallic God n.d. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Manhood: The Beknighted Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Manhood: The Renaissance Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Manhood: The Gun Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Manhood: The Divine Machine Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Manhood: The Psyche of Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Manhood: The Primitive Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Manhood: The Media Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Manhood: The Scientific Super Man n.d. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Manhood: seminar outlines n.d. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Manhood: notes n.d. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - The Masks of Mohacs [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - The Masks of Mohacs [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - The Mexican Americans [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - The Mexican Americans [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 26)
    TMs, 76 pp.
  - The Mexican Americans [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 13, Folder 27)
    TMs, 72 pp.
  - The Mexican Americans: London n.d. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - The Mexican Americans: notes 1978 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Mother Earth and Father Energy [1 of 2] 1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Mother Earth and Father Energy [2 of 2] 1983 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mother Earth and Father Energy. Across the Board.--Vol. 20, no. 7 1983 July -Aug. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The Mountains of Manhood; or, Where men were men n.d. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Murieta: Newport and Latta n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Murieta: notes [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Murieta: notes [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Murieta: prints and photos n.d. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Murieta: reference and addresses n.d. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Murieta: maps [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Murieta: maps [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Murieta: clippings et al. n.d. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Murieta: corridos n.d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - My Dream of the Night [The Spirit Woman: Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - My House was your House: The Santa Fe Story n.d. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    TMs, 13 pp.
  - The Myths of America: a book proposal n.d. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - The Myths of America: a review of "cowboy: The Enduring Myth of the Wild West," by Russell Martin n.d. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    TMs (3 copies), 13 pp.
  - The Myths of America [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    TMs, 26 pp.
  - The Myths of America [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - The Myths of America [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Nation of Nations: research materials [1 of 4] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Nation of Nations: research materials [2 of 4] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Nation of Nations: research materials [3 of 4] n.d. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Nation of Nations: research materials [4 of 4] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Nation of Nations: book proposal n.d. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Native American Series: Harper and Row 1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    "Thoughts on the Native American Publishing Program, and its future," TMs, 7 pp.
  - The New Indians n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The New Indians: notes [1 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The New Indians: notes [2 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - The New Indians: notes [3 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - The New Indians: notes [4 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The New Indians: notes [5 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The New Indians: notes [6 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The New Indians: notes [7 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The New Indians: notes [8 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - The New Indians: notes [9 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - The New Indians: notes [10 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - The New Indians: notes [11 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - The New Indians: notes [12 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - The New Indians: notes [13 of 13] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - The New Indians: publicity n.d. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - The New Indians: photos and drawings n.d. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - The New Indians: back flap copy n.d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - The New Daily Worker: What? n.d. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper in an unwritten language n.d. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - New York Times Book Review: Western Writers [1 of 2] 1985 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    "The Western Writers Revive an old tradition," TMs, 10 pp.
  - New York Times Book Review: Western Writers [2 of 2] 1985 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    "Shadows over the adobes," TMs, 16 pp.
  - None of us are native to this place n.d. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - None of us are native to this place n.d. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - None of us are native to this place n.d. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - No one hears our silence [A long hot winter in the vineyards] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: Wa Wa Chaw diary n.d. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: The New Indians n.d. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: contents n.d. (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: work notes y questions [Wa Wa Chaw poems] [1 of 4] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: work notes y questions [2 of 4] n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: work notes y questions[3 of 4] n.d. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: work notes y questions [4 of 4] n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: more notes [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: more notes [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: prologue n.d. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: I. The Child Victim of Being Born n.d. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    TMs, 38 pp.
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: II. The Freak n.d. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: III. My Paleface Mother n.d. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: IV. My Paleface Father n.d. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    TMs, 33 pp.
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: V. The Spider and the Fly n.d. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: VI. On Becoming a Woman n.d. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: VII. The Ungodly Looking Young Man n.d. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    TMs, 29 pp.
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: VIII. The Pain of Love n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: IX. The Creative Mind n.d. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: X. Nature is not interested in the scheme of things n.d. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XI. And I had no knowledge of what a reservation was n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XII. My People: The Women n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XIII. My People: The Men n.d. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XIV. My People: The Children n.d. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XV. Many different colored people n.d. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XVI. The strange white Gods n.d. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XVII. The White Wars n.d. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XVIII. The White Government n.d. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XIX. In the City n.d. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XX. The City Indians n.d. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XXI. The Artificial Indians n.d. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XXII. The Lone Wolf: Carlos Montezuma n.d. (Box 17, Folder 11)